Guide to the Common Woman Chorus Records, 1985-2015 and undated RL.00250
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Common Woman Chorus records
1985-2015 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Common Woman Chorus
RL.00250
15.0 Linear Feet
Lesbian feminist choral group established in the Durham-Raleigh-Chapel Hill area (N.C.) in 1983. The Common Woman Chorus records contain material dating from 1985 to 2010. The records primarily comprise sheet music, concert programs, publicity, correspondence, and administrative records. Although the records contain mostly print material, they also include some color photographs, audiocassettes, videos, electronic word documents, t-shirts, and sweatshirts. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Researchers wishing to use membership materials that contain personal information must secure written permission from the president of the organization or designee before access may be granted by the libray.
Original audiovisual recordings in this collection are not immediately accessible because they require further processing before use.
Please note that all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Common Woman Chorus Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gifts from 2004-2017.
Biographical Note
The Common Woman Chorus, founded in 1983 and based in the Durham-Raleigh-Chapel Hill area of North Carolina, performs musical selections that highlight the diversity and strength of women's lives and experiences. The Common Woman Chorus took its name from a Judy Grahn poem that reads, A common woman is as common as a common loaf of bread...and will rise. The chorus frequently combines political activism and music by performing at benefits for progressive organizations. The mission of the Common Woman Chorus is to entertain and educate the local community while refining musical skills and developing friendships.
Collection Overview
The Common Woman Chorus records contain material dating from 1985 to 2015 relating to the group's musical and fund-raising activities. The records primarily comprise sheet music, concert programs, publicity, correspondence, and administrative records. Although the records contain mostly print material, a few color photographs, audiocassettes, videos, electronic word documents, t-shirts, and sweathirts are also included. Use copies of original audiovisual recordings will need to be created before items can be accessed by researchers. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Related Material
Atlanta Lesbian Feminist Alliance (ALFA) Archives
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Charis Books and More - Charis Circle Records
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Ladyslipper, Inc. Records
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Flyers (printed matter); Lesbians -- United States; Machine-readable records; North Carolina -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Audiocassettes; Choruses (Women's voices); Feminism -- United States; Sheet music; Women's music; Common Woman Chorus; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Common Woman Chorus Records, 1985-2015 and undated, 15 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by folder title, followed by audiovisual and oversize material. Original folder titles were retained.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  [Original recordings are closed to research. Use copies need to be created before contents can be accessed.]
  - ASCAP information/forms, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Board, 1987-2004 (Box 1)
  - Board bylaws, undated (Box 1)
  - Broadway Our Way, undated (Box 1)
  - Business documents, 2000 and undated (Box 1)
  - Cabaret, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Catalogs, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Chorus, 1985-1999 and undated (Box 1)
  - Chorus business, 1996-2001 (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Concert notes, 1996-2002 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Concert programs, 1994-2004 (Box 1)
  - Concerts and fundraisers, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1997-2002 (Box 2)
  - Emcee script sample, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Ephemera, 2001-2015 and undated (Box 16)
  - ERUUF (Eno River Unitarian-Universal Fellowship) rental, 1992-1999 (Box 2)
  - Farewell to Eleanor, 2001 Jan. 27 (Box 2)
  - Financial reports, 1985-2003 (Box 2)
  - Financial files, 2001-2006 (Box 14)
  - Financial records, 2007-2014 (Box 15)
  - Financial records, 2014-2015 (Box 16)
  - Flyer file, 1992-2002 and undated (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Flyer/program ideas, 1993-2001 and undated (Box 2)
  - GALA (Gay and Lesbian Association of Choruses), 1997-2002 (Box 2)
  - GALA handbook, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Grant writing, 2002 and undated (Box 3)
  - Handbooks and forms, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Historic, 1986-1996 and undated (Box 3)
  - Introductions to music, 1998-1999 and undated (Box 3)
  - Julia Storm files, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Julia Storm files, 2005-2008 (Box 17)
  - Legal documents, 1986-2001 (Box 3)
  - LGBT newsletters and information, 2001-2002 and undated (Box 3)
  - Love Love Love, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
  - Music selection committee, 1995-2002 and undated (folders 1-3 of 9) (Box 3)
  - Music selection committee, 1995-2002 and undated (folders 4-9 of 9) (Box 4)
  - Music selection committee orders, 2000 and undated (Box 4)
  - New documents, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Non-profit, 2001 and undated (Box 4)
  - Other choruses, 2000-2003 and undated (Box 4)
  - Photographs, circa 1997 and undated (Box 5)
  - Printed material, 2001-2015 and undated (Box 16)
  - Publicity committee, 2000-2001 and undated (Box 5)
  - Rosters, 1995-2001 and undated (Box 5)
    Researchers wishing to use membership materials that contain personal information must secure written permission from the president of the organization or designee before access may be granted by the libray.
  - Sheet music (folders 1-8 of 29) (Box 5)
  - Sheet music (folders 9-15 of 29) (Box 6)
  - Sheet music (folders 16-22 of 29) (Box 7)
  - Sheet music (folders 23-28 of 29) (Box 8)
  - Sheet music (folder 29 of 29) (Box 9)
  - Surveys, 2000-2003 and undated (Box 9)
  - Audio cassettes, 1996 and undated (Box 9)
    [Original recordings are closed to use. Listening copies must be made before contents can be accessed.]
  - Audio cassettes, 2001-2015 (Box 18)
    General
    Performances and music used by Common Woman Chorus
  - Video, The Eleanor Sableski Era, 1983-2001 (Box 9)
    [Use copy needs to be created before item can be accessed for research.]
  - Oversize material (Box 10)
    Box contains t-shirts and sweatshirts, a few large digital prints, and music selection committee notes on a piece of cardboard.
  - Electronic files (Disk 1)
    The majority of these are routine one-page documents outlining the responsibilities of various Common Woman Chorus committee leaders.
- Accession (2011-0187), 1992-2010, 3 boxes
  Sheet music, board meeting notes, planning materials, and audio recordings of Common Woman Chorus concerts and events, largely dating from the late 1990s and early 2000s. The largest batch of material relates to the planning and advertising of Raising Our Voices: A Breast Cancer Benefit concert held by CWC in November 2004. Also includes flyers, publicity materials, t-shirts, and correspondence between chorus members, as well as notes and internal documentation kept by chorus secretary Betty Prioux.
  Arrangement note
  Materials are arranged thematically by event and format, and are in loose chronological order. Audiovisual materials will need to be reformatted prior to use.
  - Events (Box 11)
    - Winter chorus concert, 1996 (Box 11)
    - ManWomanThing concert with Triangle Gay Men's Chorus, 1997 June 7 (Box 11)
    - Eleanor's final concert directing, 2001 Jan. 27 (Box 11)
    - Raising Our Voices: A Breast Cancer Benefit Concert, 2004 November
      - Brainstorming notes (Box 11)
      - Fundraising, 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Fundraising: Drug companies (Box 11)
      - Fundraising: Sponsors and donors (Box 11)
      - Fundraising: Sponsorship requests (Box 11)
      - Fundraising: Grants (Box 11)
      - Fundraising: Letters (Box 11)
      - Tickets (Box 11)
      - BTI contract information (Box 11)
      - Emails about planning, 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Concert publicity drafts (Box 11)
      - Concert publicity (Box 11)
      - Publicity plans (Box 11)
      - Advertisements (Box 11)
      - News clippings (Box 11)
      - Breast Cancer Resource Directory, 2nd and 3rd editions, 2004-2007, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Breast Cancer Resource Directory website, 2004 (Box 11)
    - Seasonal programs, 2003-2005 (Box 11)
    - Love and Marriage musical, 2005 (Box 11)
    - Brochures and publicity for CWC events, 1996-2009, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Sheet music, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - General administration (Box 12)
    - General emails, board meetings, flyers, and correspondence, 1994-2006, 5 folders (Box 12)
    - ERUUF contract correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 12)
    - Board retreat planning, 2006 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2003-2008 (Box 12)
    - Chorus attendance sheets and rosters, 1996-2006 (Box 12)
    - Announcements, 2010 (Box 12)
    - Sister Singers Network information and brochures, 1998-2010 (Box 12)
    - GALA materials, 2001-2002 (Box 12)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous ephermera and notes, undated (Box 12)
    - Board retreat notes, 2002 (Box 13)
  - T-shirts (3) and Homo Depot apron (1) (Box 13)
  - Audiovisual recordings
    - CDs
      - Love and Marriage, 2005 (5) (Box 13)
      - Angela and Michelle's Holiday Compilation, 2005 (Box 13)
      - Christmas concert, 2002 (Box 13)
      - Peace and Justice, 2007 (2) (Box 13)
      - Raising Our Voices, 2004 (Box 13)
      - Christmas concert, undated (Box 13)
      - Bingham Center, 2007 (Box 13)
      - Loose Tooth, undated (Box 13)
      - Let's Go To the Movies, 2009 (Box 13)
      - Identity Cafe practice, 2008 (Box 13)
      - Rehearsal, 2009 (Box 13)
      - ManWomanThing, 1997 (Box 13)
      - XSL Publishing backup (Box 13)
    - Cassettes
      - Soprano II, undated (2) (Box 13)
      - Soprano I: Love Love Love, undated (Box 13)
      - Winter concert, 1992 (Box 13)
      - Winter concert, 1993 (Box 13)
    - VHS
      - Sisters, Spring 2000 (Box 13)